Thomas/PERSON Stanley/PERSON Holland/PERSON (/O born/O 1/O June/O 1996/O )/O is/O an/O English/O actor/O ./O 
His/O accolades/O include/O a/O British/O Academy/O Film/O Award/O and/O three/O Saturn/O Awards/O ./O 
He/O featured/O on/O the/O Forbes/ORGANIZATION 30/O Under/O 30/O Europe/LOCATION list/O of/O 2019/O ./O 
Some/O publications/O have/O called/O him/O one/O of/O the/O most/O popular/O actors/O of/O his/O generation/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON made/O his/O film/O debut/O in/O the/O disaster/O drama/O The/O Impossible/O (/O 2012/O )/O as/O a/O teenage/O tourist/O trapped/O in/O a/O tsunami/O ,/O for/O which/O he/O received/O critical/O acclaim/O and/O a/O nomination/O for/O the/O Goya/O Award/O for/O Best/O New/O Actor/O ./O 
After/O this/O ,/O Holland/PERSON decided/O to/O pursue/O acting/O as/O a/O full/O -/O time/O career/O ,/O appearing/O in/O How/O I/O Live/O Now/O (/O 2013/O )/O and/O playing/O historical/O figures/O in/O the/O film/O In/O the/O Heart/O of/O the/O Sea/O (/O 2015/O )/O and/O the/O miniseries/O Wolf/PERSON Hall/O (/O 2015/O )/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON achieved/O international/O recognition/O playing/O Spider/O -/O Man/O in/O six/O Marvel/O Cinematic/O Universe/O (/O MCU/O )/O superhero/O films/O ,/O beginning/O with/O Captain/O America/O :/O Civil/O War/O (/O 2016/O )/O ./O 
The/O following/O year/O ,/O Holland/PERSON received/O the/O BAFTA/O Rising/O Star/O Award/O and/O became/O the/O youngest/O actor/O to/O play/O a/O title/O role/O in/O an/O MCU/O film/O in/O Spider/O -/O Man/O :/O Homecoming/O ./O 
The/O sequels/O ,/O subtitled/O Far/O From/O Home/O (/O 2019/O )/O and/O No/O Way/O Home/O (/O 2021/O )/O ,/O each/O grossed/O more/O than/O $/O 1/O billion/O worldwide/O ,/O and/O the/O latter/O became/O the/O highest/O -/O grossing/O film/O of/O the/O year/O ./O 
He/O had/O another/O action/O film/O role/O in/O Uncharted/O (/O 2022/O )/O ,/O and/O also/O expanded/O to/O play/O against/O -/O type/O roles/O in/O the/O crime/O dramas/O The/O Devil/O All/O the/O Time/O (/O 2020/O )/O and/O Cherry/O (/O 2021/O )/O ./O 
Holland/LOCATION has/O additionally/O directed/O the/O short/O film/O Tweet/O (/O 2015/O )/O and/O voiced/O roles/O in/O animated/O features/O ,/O including/O Spies/O in/O Disguise/O (/O 2019/O )/O and/O Onward/O (/O 2020/O )/O ./O 
Early/O life/O and/O education/O Thomas/PERSON Stanley/PERSON Holland/PERSON was/O born/O on/O 1/O June/O 1996/O in/O Kingston/LOCATION upon/O Thames/O ,/O in/O Surrey/LOCATION ,/O to/O photographer/O Nicola/O (/O née/O Frost/O )/O and/O Dominic/PERSON Holland/PERSON ,/O a/O comedian/O and/O author/O ./O 
He/O has/O three/O younger/O brothers/O ./O 
His/O paternal/O grandmother/O was/O from/O County/LOCATION Tipperary/LOCATION ,/O Ireland/LOCATION ,/O and/O his/O paternal/O grandfather/O was/O from/O the/O Isle/O of/O Man/O ./O 
He/O lives/O in/O Kingston/LOCATION upon/O Thames/O ,/O near/O the/O house/O of/O his/O parents/O and/O younger/O brothers/O ./O 
As/O his/O parents/O have/O creative/O professions/O ,/O he/O is/O often/O inspired/O by/O them/O ;/O he/O considers/O his/O father/O a/O role/O model/O who/O has/O unofficially/O worked/O as/O his/O manager/O due/O to/O his/O experience/O in/O the/O industry/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON was/O educated/O at/O Donhead/LOCATION ,/O an/O all/O -/O male/O Catholic/ORGANIZATION preparatory/O school/O in/O Wimbledon/LOCATION in/O south/LOCATION west/LOCATION London/LOCATION ./O 
When/O he/O was/O seven/O ,/O he/O was/O diagnosed/O with/O dyslexia/O ./O 
His/O parents/O sent/O him/O and/O his/O brothers/O (/O to/O avoid/O making/O them/O feel/O neglected/O )/O to/O a/O private/O school/O so/O he/O could/O get/O the/O necessary/O attention/O ./O 
Although/O Holland/PERSON liked/O the/O new/O school/O ,/O this/O started/O to/O drain/O his/O family/O 's/O finances/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON attended/O Wimbledon/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O voluntary/O aided/O Jesuit/O comprehensive/O school/O ,/O followed/O by/O the/O BRIT/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Performing/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Technology/ORGANIZATION in/O Croydon/LOCATION ./O 
Growing/O up/O ,/O Holland/PERSON considered/O several/O career/O choices/O ./O 
As/O a/O child/O ,/O he/O was/O a/O fan/O of/O Janet/PERSON Jackson/PERSON 's/O songs/O ,/O and/O often/O danced/O to/O them/O ./O 
His/O mother/O signed/O him/O up/O for/O a/O dancing/O class/O advertised/O in/O the/O private/O school/O Holland/LOCATION was/O visiting/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
In/O his/O teens/O ,/O Holland/PERSON briefly/O attended/O carpentry/O school/O in/O Cardiff/LOCATION ,/O Wales/LOCATION ./O 
He/O also/O considered/O becoming/O a/O primary/O school/O teacher/O ,/O as/O he/O enjoys/O being/O around/O children/O ./O 
Career/O 2006/O –/O 2014/O :/O Early/O stage/O work/O and/O film/O debut/O At/O age/O nine/O ,/O Holland/PERSON began/O dancing/O at/O a/O hip/O hop/O class/O at/O Nifty/ORGANIZATION Feet/ORGANIZATION Dance/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O Wimbledon/LOCATION ,/O where/O he/O performed/O with/O his/O school/O group/O at/O the/O 2006/O Richmond/O Dance/O Festival/O ./O 
There/O ,/O he/O was/O spotted/O by/O choreographer/O Lynne/PERSON Page/PERSON ,/O an/O associate/O to/O Peter/PERSON Darling/PERSON ,/O choreographer/O of/O Billy/PERSON Elliot/PERSON the/O Musical/O ./O 
Page/O arranged/O an/O audition/O for/O Holland/LOCATION ,/O where/O the/O musical/O 's/O director/O Stephen/PERSON Daldry/PERSON thought/O that/O he/O "/O had/O great/O potential/O and/O was/O a/O very/O natural/O actor/O "/O ./O 
After/O two/O years/O of/O training/O in/O ballet/O ,/O tap/O dancing/O and/O acrobatics/O ,/O Holland/PERSON won/O the/O role/O of/O Michael/PERSON Caffrey/PERSON ,/O the/O protagonist/O 's/O best/O friend/O ,/O and/O made/O his/O debut/O performance/O at/O the/O West/LOCATION End/LOCATION 's/LOCATION Victoria/LOCATION Palace/LOCATION Theatre/LOCATION in/O June/O 2008/O ./O 
During/O his/O time/O performing/O in/O the/O musical/O ,/O Holland/PERSON learned/O gymnastics/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON says/O when/O his/O peers/O at/O school/O found/O out/O about/O his/O dancing/O activities/O ,/O they/O started/O bullying/O him/O ./O 
Later/O in/O 2008/O ,/O Holland/LOCATION and/O co-star/O Tanner/PERSON Pflueger/PERSON were/O promoted/O to/O the/O lead/O role/O in/O the/O musical/O ./O 
On/O his/O first/O day/O playing/O Elliot/PERSON ,/O Holland/LOCATION developed/O tonsillitis/O but/O performed/O on/O stage/O anyway/O to/O positive/O reviews/O ;/O he/O went/O to/O the/O doctor/O the/O next/O day/O ./O 
Following/O his/O stage/O success/O ,/O Holland/PERSON hoped/O to/O be/O popular/O in/O school/O and/O that/O his/O schoolmates/O would/O stop/O bullying/O him/O ./O 
After/O being/O in/O a/O professional/O environment/O ,/O he/O matured/O earlier/O than/O his/O peers/O and/O struggled/O to/O fit/O in/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O his/O GCSE/O grades/O suffered/O ./O 
After/O his/O work/O on/O Billy/PERSON Elliot/PERSON the/O Musical/O finished/O in/O 2010/O ,/O Holland/PERSON voiced/O a/O role/O in/O the/O British/O dub/O of/O the/O Japanese/O animated/O fantasy/O film/O Arrietty/O (/O 2011/O )/O ,/O and/O sent/O an/O audition/O tape/O to/O Juan/PERSON Antonio/PERSON Bayona/PERSON for/O a/O part/O in/O The/O Impossible/O (/O 2012/O )/O ./O 
Bayona/PERSON then/O arranged/O a/O meeting/O ,/O and/O had/O Holland/PERSON write/O a/O letter/O to/O his/O mother/O and/O recite/O it/O as/O an/O audition/O ./O 
Impressed/O with/O his/O emotional/O delivery/O ,/O Bayona/PERSON cast/O Holland/LOCATION in/O the/O film/O ./O 
In/O The/O Impossible/O ,/O Holland/PERSON played/O a/O teenager/O trapped/O with/O his/O family/O in/O the/O 2004/O Indian/LOCATION Ocean/LOCATION earthquake/O and/O tsunami/O ./O 
Transitioning/O from/O stage/O to/O screen/O was/O initially/O hard/O for/O Holland/LOCATION due/O to/O the/O shift/O from/O live/O audience/O to/O camera/O ./O 
He/O and/O co-star/O Naomi/PERSON Watts/PERSON filmed/O scenes/O in/O a/O 35,000/O -/O gallon/O water/O tank/O ,/O which/O were/O physically/O and/O psychologically/O taxing/O for/O them/O ./O 
Working/O with/O Watts/PERSON made/O Holland/LOCATION realise/O that/O he/O wanted/O to/O pursue/O an/O acting/O career/O permanently/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON received/O critical/O praise/O for/O his/O performance/O ./O 
A./PERSON O./PERSON Scott/PERSON of/O The/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION found/O Holland/LOCATION to/O be/O "/O a/O terrific/O young/O actor/O "/O ,/O praising/O his/O character/O 's/O transition/O from/O a/O self/O -/O involved/O to/O a/O responsible/O adolescent/O ./O 
He/O won/O several/O awards/O ,/O including/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Board/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Review/ORGANIZATION Award/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Breakthrough/ORGANIZATION Performance/ORGANIZATION and/O London/O Film/O Critics/O Circle/O Award/O for/O Young/O British/O Performer/O of/O the/O Year/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON featured/O in/O the/O drama/O film/O How/O I/O Live/O Now/O (/O 2013/O )/O ,/O lent/O his/O voice/O in/O a/O supporting/O role/O for/O the/O drama/O film/O Locke/PERSON (/O 2013/O )/O ,/O and/O had/O a/O cameo/O in/O Billy/PERSON Elliot/PERSON the/O Musical/O Live/O (/O 2014/O )/O ./O 
2015/O –/O 2017/O :/O Breakthrough/O as/O Spider/O -/O Man/O Holland/PERSON appeared/O in/O four/O episodes/O of/O BBC/ORGANIZATION Two/O 's/O historical/O miniseries/O Wolf/PERSON Hall/O (/O 2015/O )/O ,/O as/O Gregory/PERSON Cromwell/PERSON ,/O son/O of/O the/O protagonist/O Thomas/PERSON Cromwell/PERSON played/O by/O Mark/PERSON Rylance/PERSON ./O 
He/O directed/O Tweet/O (/O 2015/O )/O ,/O a/O 3/O -/O minute/O short/O film/O about/O a/O young/O man/O building/O a/O birdhouse/O with/O his/O grandfather/O ;/O Holland/LOCATION later/O expressed/O an/O interest/O in/O directing/O feature/O films/O in/O his/O 40s/O ./O 
Also/O in/O 2015/O ,/O Holland/PERSON co-starred/O as/O the/O teenage/O sailor/O Thomas/PERSON Nickerson/PERSON in/O Ron/PERSON Howard/PERSON 's/O historical/O adventure/O -/O drama/O In/O the/O Heart/O of/O the/O Sea/O ./O 
The/O film/O is/O based/O on/O the/O namesake/O 2000/O non-fiction/O book/O about/O the/O sinking/O of/O the/O American/O whaling/O ship/O Essex/ORGANIZATION in/O 1820/O ./O 
In/O preparation/O ,/O he/O and/O co-stars/O ,/O including/O Chris/PERSON Hemsworth/PERSON ,/O lost/O significant/O weight/O ,/O consuming/O 500/O –/O 1,000/O calories/O a/O day/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON performed/O most/O of/O his/O stunts/O in/O the/O film/O ./O 
In/O the/O Heart/O of/O the/O Sea/O received/O mixed/O reviews/O from/O critics/O ,/O and/O grossed/O $/O 93/O million/O against/O a/O $/O 100/O million/O budget/O ./O 
Brian/PERSON Truitt/PERSON of/O the/O USA/ORGANIZATION Today/ORGANIZATION wrote/O that/O Holland/LOCATION "/O does/O a/O good/O job/O "/O ./O 
In/O June/O 2015/O ,/O Holland/PERSON signed/O a/O six/O -/O picture/O deal/O with/O Marvel/ORGANIZATION Studios/ORGANIZATION to/O play/O a/O teenage/O Peter/PERSON Parker/PERSON //O Spider/O -/O Man/O ./O 
Growing/O up/O ,/O Holland/LOCATION was/O a/O fan/O of/O Spider/O -/O Man/O ;/O he/O owned/O 30/O costumes/O and/O bed/O sheet/O covers/O of/O the/O character/O ./O 
He/O auditioned/O against/O 1,500/O teenagers/O worldwide/O ,/O including/O English/O actors/O Charlie/PERSON Rowe/PERSON and/O Asa/PERSON Butterfield/PERSON ./O 
While/O producers/O Kevin/PERSON Feige/PERSON and/O Amy/PERSON Pascal/PERSON were/O impressed/O with/O his/O performances/O in/O The/O Impossible/O ,/O Wolf/LOCATION Hall/LOCATION ,/O and/O In/O the/O Heart/O of/O the/O Sea/O ,/O directors/O the/O Russo/PERSON brothers/O cited/O Holland/LOCATION 's/O dancing/O and/O gymnastics/O background/O as/O the/O reasons/O to/O cast/O him/O ./O 
Stan/PERSON Lee/PERSON ,/O Spider/O -/O Man/O 's/O creator/O ,/O said/O Holland/PERSON was/O the/O "/O exact/O age/O and/O height/O "/O when/O he/O envisioned/O the/O character/O ./O 
As/O part/O of/O the/O Marvel/O Cinematic/O Universe/O (/O MCU/O )/O ,/O he/O first/O appeared/O as/O Spider/O -/O Man/O in/O Captain/O America/O :/O Civil/O War/O (/O 2016/O )/O ./O 
The/O film/O was/O a/O critical/O and/O commercial/O success/O ,/O grossing/O over/O $/O 1.1/O billion/O worldwide/O against/O a/O budget/O of/O $/O 250/O million/O to/O become/O the/O highest/O -/O grossing/O film/O of/O 2016/O ./O 
In/O a/O review/O for/O The/O Guardian/O ,/O Peter/PERSON Bradshaw/PERSON praised/O Holland/LOCATION and/O co-star/O Paul/PERSON Rudd/PERSON (/O who/O played/O Ant/O -/O Man/O )/O as/O "/O seductively/O high/O -/O spirited/O and/O hilarious/O "/O ,/O and/O Richard/PERSON Roeper/PERSON of/O Chicago/ORGANIZATION Sun/ORGANIZATION -/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION wrote/O that/O he/O made/O "/O a/O strong/O first/O impression/O "/O as/O Spider/O -/O Man/O ./O 
In/O 2016/O ,/O Holland/PERSON co-starred/O with/O Joel/PERSON Kinnaman/PERSON and/O Percy/PERSON Hynes/PERSON White/PERSON in/O the/O psychological/O thriller/O Edge/O of/O Winter/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O first/O film/O he/O did/O without/O his/O parents/O '/O knowledge/O ./O 
Frank/PERSON Scheck/PERSON of/O The/O Hollywood/O Reporter/O found/O Holland/LOCATION and/O White/O "/O excellent/O "/O ,/O describing/O their/O terrified/O reaction/O as/O "/O more/O emotionally/O wrenching/O than/O the/O tired/O thriller/O genre/O conventions/O to/O which/O the/O film/O ultimately/O succumbs/O "/O ./O 
At/O the/O 70th/O British/O Academy/O Film/O Awards/O in/O 2017/O ,/O Holland/LOCATION won/O the/O Rising/O Star/O Award/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON 's/O first/O work/O that/O year/O was/O alongside/O Charlie/PERSON Hunnam/PERSON in/O James/PERSON Gray/PERSON 's/O drama/O The/O Lost/O City/O of/O Z/O ,/O which/O was/O released/O to/O positive/O reviews/O ./O 
On/O his/O last/O day/O of/O filming/O ,/O he/O broke/O his/O nose/O after/O a/O failed/O backflip/O attempt/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON played/O the/O son/O of/O Percy/PERSON Fawcett/PERSON (/O Hunnam/PERSON )/O ,/O an/O explorer/O who/O makes/O several/O attempts/O to/O find/O a/O supposed/O lost/O ancient/O city/O in/O the/O Amazon/LOCATION rainforest/O ./O 
Neil/PERSON Soans/PERSON of/O The/O Times/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION India/ORGANIZATION praised/O Holland/LOCATION for/O making/O the/O film/O emotional/O towards/O the/O end/O and/O Rex/PERSON Reed/PERSON of/O The/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Observer/ORGANIZATION found/O him/O "/O remarkably/O strong/O and/O self/O -/O assured/O "/O ./O 
Later/O in/O 2017/O ,/O Holland/LOCATION played/O Samuel/PERSON Insull/PERSON in/O Alfonso/PERSON Gomez/PERSON -/O Rejon/O 's/O The/O Current/O War/O ,/O which/O received/O negative/O reviews/O and/O was/O a/O box/O -/O office/O failure/O ./O 
Clarisse/PERSON Loughrey/PERSON of/O The/O Independent/O found/O Holland/LOCATION 's/O role/O insubstantial/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON 's/O second/O film/O in/O 2017/O was/O his/O solo/O feature/O as/O the/O title/O character/O in/O Spider/O -/O Man/O :/O Homecoming/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O Holland/PERSON earned/O an/O entry/O in/O Guinness/O Book/O of/O World/O Records/O as/O the/O youngest/O actor/O to/O play/O a/O title/O role/O in/O the/O MCU/O ./O 
Though/O Holland/PERSON took/O some/O inspiration/O from/O previous/O Spider/O -/O Man/O actors/O Tobey/PERSON Maguire/PERSON and/O Andrew/PERSON Garfield/PERSON ,/O he/O wanted/O to/O add/O some/O newness/O in/O his/O reinterpretation/O of/O the/O character/O ./O 
Homecoming/O focused/O on/O Parker/PERSON ,/O as/O he/O tries/O to/O balance/O being/O a/O high/O -/O school/O student/O and/O a/O superhero/O ./O 
To/O prepare/O ,/O Holland/PERSON attended/O The/O Bronx/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Science/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O Bronx/LOCATION for/O a/O few/O days/O ,/O although/O other/O students/O did/O not/O believe/O he/O was/O cast/O as/O Spider/O -/O Man/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON felt/O this/O situation/O reflected/O the/O film/O 's/O story/O ,/O in/O which/O other/O characters/O are/O unaware/O that/O Parker/PERSON is/O Spider/O -/O Man/O ./O 
Homecoming/O and/O Holland/LOCATION 's/O performance/O received/O positive/O reviews/O ./O 
Peter/PERSON Travers/PERSON called/O it/O "/O a/O star/O performance/O given/O by/O a/O born/O actor/O "/O ./O 
Made/O on/O a/O budget/O of/O $/O 175/O million/O ,/O the/O film/O grossed/O over/O $/O 800/O million/O worldwide/O ./O 
Holland/LOCATION 's/O final/O role/O in/O 2017/O was/O in/O the/O Irish/O film/O Pilgrimage/O ,/O which/O premiered/O at/O the/O Tribeca/O Film/O Festival/O ./O 
Outside/O film/O that/O year/O ,/O Holland/PERSON appeared/O with/O Zendaya/PERSON on/O Paramount/ORGANIZATION Network/ORGANIZATION 's/O Lip/O Sync/O Battle/O ,/O during/O which/O he/O performed/O Rhianna/PERSON 's/O "/O Umbrella/O "/O in/O drag/O ./O 
His/O parents/O founded/O The/O Brothers/ORGANIZATION Trust/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O charitable/O organisation/O ,/O which/O aims/O to/O use/O his/O popularity/O to/O raise/O funds/O for/O humanitarian/O causes/O ./O 
2018/O –/O present/O :/O Commercial/O success/O Holland/PERSON reprised/O his/O role/O as/O Spider/O -/O Man/O in/O Avengers/O :/O Infinity/O War/O (/O 2018/O )/O and/O its/O follow/O -/O up/O Avengers/O :/O Endgame/O (/O 2019/O )/O ,/O which/O were/O filmed/O back/O -/O to/O -/O back/O ./O 
The/O pictures/O each/O earned/O more/O than/O $/O 2/O billion/O ,/O and/O Endgame/O briefly/O became/O the/O highest/O -/O grossing/O film/O of/O all/O time/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON followed/O with/O the/O sequel/O Spider/O -/O Man/O :/O Far/O From/O Home/O (/O 2019/O )/O ,/O which/O widely/O received/O positive/O reviews/O and/O became/O the/O first/O Spider/O -/O Man/O film/O to/O earn/O $/O 1/O billion/O ,/O finishing/O as/O the/O fourth/O -/O highest/O grosser/O of/O 2019/O ./O 
Ben/PERSON Travis/PERSON of/O Empire/O magazine/O found/O Holland/LOCATION "/O a/O note/O -/O perfect/O Spider/O -/O Man/O —/O still/O funnier/O and/O more/O believably/O teenage/O "/O than/O Maguire/PERSON and/O Garfield/PERSON who/O previously/O portrayed/O the/O character/O ./O 
Travis/PERSON wrote/O ,/O "/O Holland/PERSON never/O loses/O the/O ebullient/O spark/O that/O makes/O him/O one/O of/O the/O MCU/ORGANIZATION 's/O most/O endearing/O figures/O ./O "/O 
Holland/PERSON received/O a/O third/O consecutive/O Saturn/O Award/O for/O Best/O Performance/O by/O a/O Younger/O Actor/O for/O Far/O From/O Home/O ,/O having/O previously/O won/O for/O Civil/O War/O and/O Homecoming/O ./O 
He/O voiced/O roles/O in/O the/O Blue/ORGANIZATION Sky/ORGANIZATION Studios/ORGANIZATION animation/O Spies/O in/O Disguise/O (/O 2019/O )/O ,/O the/O live/O -/O action/O film/O Dolittle/O (/O 2020/O )/O ,/O and/O the/O Pixar/O animated/O film/O Onward/O (/O 2020/O )/O ./O 
The/O last/O two/O were/O with/O his/O MCU/O co-stars/O Robert/PERSON Downey/PERSON Jr./PERSON and/O Chris/PERSON Pratt/PERSON ,/O respectively/O ./O 
Made/O on/O lucrative/O budgets/O ,/O all/O three/O films/O underperformed/O at/O the/O box/O -/O office/O ./O 
Alongside/O Avengers/O co-star/O Sebastian/PERSON Stan/PERSON ,/O Holland/PERSON starred/O in/O Antonio/PERSON Campos/PERSON 's/O The/O Devil/O All/O the/O Time/O (/O 2020/O )/O ,/O a/O Netflix/ORGANIZATION psychological/O thriller/O set/O after/O World/O War/O II/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON said/O he/O initially/O worried/O that/O he/O lacked/O the/O depth/O to/O play/O a/O young/O orphaned/O man/O who/O goes/O on/O a/O killing/O spree/O ,/O and/O was/O scared/O and/O nervous/O on/O his/O first/O day/O on/O set/O ./O 
Encouraged/O by/O Campos/PERSON ,/O he/O ultimately/O enjoyed/O playing/O the/O part/O ,/O although/O it/O took/O a/O temporary/O toll/O on/O his/O mental/O health/O ./O 
Campos/PERSON praised/O Holland/LOCATION 's/O effort/O to/O learn/O Southern/O American/O English/O for/O the/O role/O ,/O described/O his/O acting/O process/O as/O "/O methodical/O "/O ,/O "/O thoughtful/O and/O sensitive/O "/O ,/O and/O called/O him/O a/O kind/O person/O ./O 
Critics/O from/O IndieWire/LOCATION and/O Roger/PERSON Ebert/PERSON 's/O website/O opined/O that/O despite/O the/O film/O 's/O failed/O script/O ,/O Holland/PERSON gave/O a/O convincing/O performance/O and/O showed/O his/O range/O as/O an/O actor/O ./O 
By/O November/O 2020/O ,/O the/O film/O was/O the/O 22nd-most/O watched/O straight/O -/O to/O -/O streaming/O title/O of/O the/O year/O ,/O according/O to/O a/O Variety/ORGANIZATION report/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON starred/O in/O three/O films/O that/O were/O released/O in/O 2021/O ./O 
His/O first/O ,/O the/O crime/O drama/O Cherry/O ,/O is/O based/O on/O the/O namesake/O novel/O by/O American/O author/O Nico/PERSON Walker/PERSON ,/O and/O reunited/O him/O with/O Avengers/ORGANIZATION directors/O Russo/PERSON brothers/O ./O 
He/O played/O a/O college/O student/O with/O post-traumatic/O stress/O disorder/O (/O PTSD/O )/O after/O enlisting/O in/O the/O army/O ,/O and/O robs/O banks/O to/O finance/O his/O drug/O addiction/O ./O 
In/O preparation/O for/O the/O role/O ,/O Holland/PERSON shaved/O his/O head/O and/O interviewed/O military/O veterans/O undergoing/O treatments/O for/O substance/O abuse/O and/O PTSD/O ./O 
He/O also/O lost/O 30/O pounds/O (/O 14/O kg/O )/O of/O weight/O ,/O then/O regained/O it/O after/O filming/O ./O 
The/O film/O was/O released/O in/O cinemas/O in/O February/O and/O digitally/O on/O Apple/ORGANIZATION TV/O +/O in/O March/O ./O 
Consensus/O among/O critics/O was/O that/O the/O film/O enabled/O Holland/LOCATION to/O broaden/O his/O horizons/O as/O an/O actor/O ,/O but/O it/O had/O a/O formulaic/O story/O ./O 
This/O was/O echoed/O by/O Owen/PERSON Gleiberman/PERSON of/O Variety/O who/O further/O noted/O that/O Holland/LOCATION proved/O his/O skills/O as/O an/O actor/O and/O demonstrated/O a/O range/O of/O indulgent/O looks/O and/O moods/O ./O 
Holland/LOCATION next/O played/O alongside/O Daisy/PERSON Ridley/PERSON as/O a/O young/O man/O living/O on/O a/O planet/O called/O New/O World/O in/O Chaos/O Walking/O ,/O an/O adaptation/O of/O Patrick/PERSON Ness/PERSON 's/O best/O -/O selling/O science/O fiction/O series/O of/O the/O same/O name/O ./O 
The/O film/O was/O delayed/O due/O to/O several/O reshoots/O in/O early/O 2019/O ,/O which/O added/O $/O 15/O million/O to/O its/O budget/O ,/O bringing/O its/O cost/O to/O $/O 100/O million/O ./O 
Chaos/O Walking/O failed/O to/O recoup/O its/O budget/O and/O received/O poor/O reviews/O ./O 
David/PERSON Rooney/PERSON of/O The/O Hollywood/LOCATION Reporter/O found/O the/O chemistry/O between/O Holland/LOCATION and/O Ridley/PERSON lackluster/O ,/O and/O Christian/ORGANIZATION Holub/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Entertainment/ORGANIZATION Weekly/ORGANIZATION noted/O his/O failed/O attempt/O to/O break/O away/O from/O roles/O similar/O to/O Spider/O -/O Man/O ./O 
In/O November/O 2021/O ,/O Holland/PERSON voiced/O Percy/PERSON Pig/PERSON in/O a/O series/O of/O advertisements/O for/O Marks/ORGANIZATION &/ORGANIZATION Spencer/ORGANIZATION 's/O Christmas/O food/O specials/O ./O 
The/O following/O month/O ,/O Holland/PERSON reprised/O his/O role/O as/O Peter/PERSON Parker/PERSON in/O the/O sequel/O Spider/O -/O Man/O :/O No/O Way/O Home/O ./O 
After/O taking/O on/O mature/O roles/O in/O films/O like/O Cherry/LOCATION ,/O Holland/PERSON noted/O that/O he/O found/O it/O strange/O adjusting/O back/O to/O playing/O Parker/PERSON ,/O chiefly/O due/O to/O raising/O his/O voice/O pitch/O and/O returning/O to/O the/O mindset/O of/O a/O "/O naïve/O ,/O charming/O teenager/O "/O ./O 
He/O described/O No/O Way/O Home/O as/O the/O "/O most/O ambitious/O standalone/O superhero/O movie/O ever/O made/O "/O ./O 
Despite/O its/O release/O during/O the/O COVID/O -/O 19/O pandemic/O ,/O No/O Way/O Home/O quickly/O emerged/O as/O the/O highest/O -/O grossing/O film/O of/O 2021/O and/O the/O sixth/O highest/O -/O grossing/O film/O of/O all/O time/O ./O 
It/O also/O became/O the/O first/O film/O since/O 2019/O 's/O Star/O Wars/O :/O The/O Rise/O of/O Skywalker/PERSON to/O earn/O more/O than/O $/O 1/O billion/O at/O the/O box/O -/O office/O ./O 
No/O Way/O Home/O became/O the/O highest/O -/O rated/O Spider/O -/O Man/O film/O on/O the/O online/O database/O IMDb/O and/O the/O review/O aggregator/O Rotten/O Tomatoes/O ./O 
Wendy/PERSON Ide/PERSON of/O The/O Guardian/O wrote/O that/O the/O film/O "/O delivers/O an/O overflowing/O ,/O funnel/O -/O web/O cornucopia/O of/O treats/O for/O Spider/O -/O fans/O "/O and/O attributed/O Parker/PERSON 's/O continuing/O appeal/O to/O "/O his/O endearing/O ,/O puppyish/O enthusiasm/O "/O ./O 
The/O Times/ORGANIZATION '/O Kevin/PERSON Maher/PERSON opined/O that/O Holland/LOCATION "/O own/O [/O s/O ]/O every/O inch/O of/O the/O role/O "/O and/O "/O casts/O his/O web/O and/O captures/O your/O heart/O "/O ./O 
Discussing/O his/O future/O as/O Spider/O -/O Man/O after/O No/O Way/O Home/O ,/O Holland/PERSON told/O GQ/O in/O 2021/O that/O he/O was/O doubtful/O about/O reprising/O the/O role/O ,/O especially/O after/O he/O turns/O 30/O in/O 2026/O ./O 
He/O expressed/O a/O desire/O to/O see/O a/O live/O -/O action/O Spider/O -/O Man/O film/O with/O Miles/PERSON Morales/PERSON as/O the/O protagonist/O ,/O whereas/O Amy/PERSON Pascal/PERSON spoke/O of/O wanting/O Holland/LOCATION to/O continue/O playing/O the/O role/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON began/O the/O following/O year/O with/O an/O investment/O in/O Dogpound/LOCATION gyms/O ,/O and/O a/O starring/O role/O as/O a/O young/O Nathan/PERSON Drake/PERSON ,/O a/O charismatic/O fortune/O hunter/O ,/O in/O the/O film/O adaptation/O of/O Naughty/O Dog/O 's/O Uncharted/O video/O game/O series/O ./O 
In/O preparation/O for/O scenes/O where/O his/O character/O is/O bartending/O ,/O Holland/PERSON worked/O shifts/O at/O the/O Chiltern/ORGANIZATION Firehouse/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O pub/O in/O London/LOCATION ./O 
Though/O the/O filming/O was/O delayed/O due/O to/O the/O COVID/O -/O 19/O pandemic/O ,/O Holland/LOCATION continued/O to/O eat/O and/O train/O for/O the/O role/O ./O 
While/O Uncharted/O polarised/O critics/O ,/O Rebecca/PERSON Rubin/PERSON of/O Variety/O wrote/O that/O Holland/LOCATION 's/O star/O -/O power/O likely/O contributed/O to/O its/O box/O -/O office/O success/O ./O 
In/O a/O mixed/O review/O for/O his/O performance/O ,/O Brian/PERSON Tallerico/PERSON of/O Roger/PERSON Ebert/PERSON 's/O website/O labelled/O him/O miscast/O ,/O writing/O that/O "/O Holland/LOCATION has/O the/O agility/O but/O quite/O simply/O lacks/O the/O weight/O and/O world/O -/O weariness/O needed/O "/O for/O the/O role/O ./O 
Holland/LOCATION next/O executive/O produced/O and/O starred/O in/O the/O Apple/ORGANIZATION TV/O +/O miniseries/O The/O Crowded/O Room/O (/O 2023/O )/O ,/O inspired/O by/O the/O 1981/O non-fiction/O novel/O The/O Minds/O of/O Billy/PERSON Milligan/PERSON ,/O in/O which/O he/O played/O a/O character/O based/O on/O Billy/PERSON Milligan/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O met/O with/O negative/O reviews/O ;/O San/ORGANIZATION Francisco/ORGANIZATION Chronicle/ORGANIZATION 's/O Bob/PERSON Strauss/PERSON dismissed/O it/O as/O "/O another/O one/O of/O Tom/PERSON Holland/PERSON 's/O '/O serious/O '/O projects/O that/O 's/O hard/O to/O take/O seriously/O "/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON said/O that/O the/O role/O proved/O to/O be/O too/O emotionally/O taxing/O for/O him/O ,/O and/O that/O he/O would/O take/O a/O year/O off/O work/O to/O recover/O ./O 
He/O made/O a/O return/O to/O the/O stage/O as/O Romeo/PERSON in/O Jamie/PERSON Lloyd/PERSON 's/O West/O End/O revival/O of/O Romeo/O and/O Juliet/O ,/O which/O ran/O for/O twelve/O weeks/O from/O May/O 2024/O ./O 
Public/O image/O Nadia/PERSON Khomami/PERSON of/O The/O Guardian/O said/O that/O Holland/LOCATION 's/O "/O cheeky/O British/O charm/O ,/O vulnerability/O and/O wit/O "/O has/O made/O him/O the/O object/O of/O infatuation/O on/O the/O internet/O ./O 
Jonathan/PERSON Dean/PERSON of/O The/ORGANIZATION Sunday/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION considered/O him/O to/O be/O "/O poised/O and/O professional/O ,/O but/O also/O so/O confident/O and/O personable/O "/O and/O took/O note/O of/O his/O maturity/O "/O despite/O boyish/O wiriness/O "/O ./O 
German/O actor/O Sönke/PERSON Möhring/PERSON ,/O his/O co-star/O from/O The/O Impossible/O ,/O similarly/O remarked/O on/O his/O professionalism/O ,/O adding/O ,/O "/O he/O is/O blessed/O with/O a/O deep/O soul/O [/O .../O ]/O down/O to/O earth/O ,/O very/O polite/O and/O a/O friendly/O kid/O ./O "/O 
Kevin/PERSON Macdonald/PERSON ,/O who/O directed/O Holland/PERSON in/O How/O I/O Live/O Now/O ,/O praised/O him/O as/O confident/O ,/O "/O articulate/O and/O enthusiastic/O "/O ,/O and/O attributed/O Holland/PERSON 's/O success/O to/O his/O positive/O energy/O ./O 
When/O asked/O about/O the/O secret/O to/O his/O success/O ,/O Holland/PERSON said/O he/O believes/O in/O avoiding/O trouble/O and/O working/O hard/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON appeared/O on/O Screen/ORGANIZATION International/ORGANIZATION 's/O "/O UK/LOCATION Stars/O of/O Tomorrow/O –/O 2012/O "/O ,/O and/O The/O Hollywood/O Reporter/O 's/O "/O Next/O Gen/O 2015/O "/O ,/O a/O list/O of/O promising/O newcomers/O in/O film/O ./O 
In/O 2019/O ,/O he/O featured/O on/O Forbes/PERSON '/O "/O 30/O Under/O 30/O Europe/LOCATION "/O ,/O a/O list/O of/O influential/O people/O under/O 30/O years/O ,/O and/O Insider/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION 's/O "/O 45/O young/O stars/O who/O will/O one/O day/O rule/O Hollywood/LOCATION "/O ./O 
After/O appearing/O on/O Glamour/O 's/O "/O Hot/O ,/O Young/O &/O British/O Actors/O 2020/O "/O ,/O he/O was/O named/O among/O the/O best/O actors/O under/O 30/O by/O Tuko/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O Complex/ORGANIZATION Networks/ORGANIZATION in/O 2021/O ./O 
In/O the/O former/O listing/O ,/O Ryan/PERSON Mutuku/PERSON described/O him/O as/O "/O a/O darling/O to/O the/O English/O media/O "/O because/O of/O his/O openness/O and/O willingness/O to/O also/O give/O interviews/O not/O related/O to/O film/O promotions/O ./O 
Calling/O him/O "/O his/O generation/O 's/O biggest/O leading/O man/O "/O in/O 2021/O ,/O GQ/ORGANIZATION 's/O Oliver/PERSON Franklin/PERSON -/PERSON Wallis/PERSON wrote/O ,/O "/O Holland/LOCATION has/O ascended/O to/O a/O tier/O of/O stardom/O few/O actors/O ever/O reach/O ,/O and/O rarely/O so/O young/O "/O ./O 
Variety/O editors/O Brent/PERSON Lang/PERSON and/O Rebecca/PERSON Rubin/PERSON reported/O in/O December/O 2021/O that/O after/O the/O success/O of/O the/O Spider/O -/O Man/O films/O ,/O Holland/PERSON could/O become/O a/O top/O -/O paid/O actor/O in/O the/O future/O ./O 
They/O noted/O the/O current/O lack/O of/O young/O leading/O men/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION and/O saw/O Holland/LOCATION 's/O potential/O to/O herald/O a/O new/O generation/O of/O successful/O actors/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON considers/O himself/O to/O be/O "/O an/O impossible/O people/O pleaser/O "/O ,/O which/O according/O to/O Olivia/ORGANIZATION Singh/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Business/ORGANIZATION Insider/ORGANIZATION has/O resulted/O in/O his/O facing/O burnout/O and/O an/O incident/O where/O he/O vomited/O after/O a/O press/O conference/O ./O 
A/O self/O -/O admittedly/O indiscreet/O person/O ,/O Holland/LOCATION has/O gained/O a/O reputation/O for/O inadvertently/O spoiling/O important/O plot/O elements/O of/O his/O films/O during/O interviews/O and/O press/O conferences/O ./O 
His/O MCU/O co-stars/O labelled/O him/O the/O "/O least/O trustworthy/O "/O cast/O member/O in/O terms/O of/O spoilers/O ./O 
To/O prevent/O an/O incident/O ,/O he/O only/O read/O parts/O of/O Captain/O America/LOCATION :/O Civil/O War/O 's/O script/O ./O 
Joe/PERSON Russo/PERSON similarly/O avoided/O giving/O Holland/LOCATION the/O script/O to/O Avengers/O :/O Endgame/O ,/O and/O Holland/PERSON knew/O only/O his/O lines/O ./O 
Holland/PERSON expressed/O his/O views/O on/O the/O film/O industry/O in/O a/O 2019/O interview/O with/O The/O Sunday/O Times/O ,/O he/O spoke/O for/O more/O representation/O of/O racial/O minorities/O and/O the/O LGBT/O community/O in/O film/O ./O 
That/O year/O ,/O when/O filmmaker/O Martin/PERSON Scorsese/PERSON criticised/O Marvel/O films/O for/O their/O lack/O of/O portraying/O human/O emotions/O ,/O Holland/PERSON responded/O :/O "/O he/O does/O n't/O know/O what/O it/O 's/O like/O because/O he/O 's/O never/O made/O one/O ./O "/O 
Holland/PERSON further/O said/O that/O MCU/O films/O will/O always/O do/O well/O commercially/O regardless/O of/O their/O quality/O ,/O whereas/O a/O bad/O independent/O film/O might/O not/O ./O 
In/O 2022/O ,/O Holland/PERSON felt/O actor/O Tom/PERSON Cruise/PERSON overlooked/O the/O commercial/O impact/O of/O Uncharted/O when/O he/O took/O credit/O for/O "/O [/O bringing/O ]/O the/O film/O industry/O back/O "/O during/O the/O COVID/O -/O 19/O pandemic/O with/O Mission/O :/O Impossible/O –/O Dead/O Reckoning/O Part/O One/O (/O 2023/O )/O ./O 
Personal/O life/O Holland/PERSON describes/O himself/O as/O a/O private/O person/O and/O is/O reluctant/O to/O discuss/O his/O personal/O life/O ./O 
He/O is/O in/O a/O relationship/O with/O his/O Spider/O -/O Man/O co-star/O Zendaya/PERSON ./O 
Holland/PERSON thought/O the/O media/O attention/O to/O their/O relationship/O breached/O their/O privacy/O and/O has/O discussed/O having/O bouts/O of/O chronic/O sleepwalking/O and/O sleep/O paralysis/O nightmares/O of/O paparazzi/O in/O his/O bedroom/O ./O 
After/O feeling/O dependent/O on/O alcohol/O in/O social/O situations/O ,/O he/O has/O been/O teetotal/O since/O participating/O in/O Dry/O January/O in/O 2022/O ./O 
Notes/O References/O External/O links/O Tom/PERSON Holland/PERSON at/O IMDb/O Tom/PERSON Holland/PERSON at/O AllMovie/O 
