Title/O :/O Jonathan/PERSON Joestar/PERSON URL/O :/O https://jojo.fandom.com/en/wiki/Jonathan_Joestar/O Personality/O :/O Personality/O “/O He/O 's/O not/O just/O looks/O and/O clothes/O ,/O but/O a/O real/O honest/O -/O to/O -/O god/O gentleman/O .../O I/O like/O it/O !/O ”/O 
—/O Speedwagon/O During/O his/O childhood/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON was/O proud/O and/O mischievous/O ,/O yet/O gentle/O ./O 
Despite/O already/O aspiring/O to/O be/O a/O "/O true/O gentleman/O "/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON lacked/O manners/O and/O mostly/O behaved/O like/O a/O normal/O child/O ./O 
His/O mother/O having/O died/O before/O he/O could/O remember/O her/O ,/O and/O his/O fellow/O boys/O ostracizing/O him/O because/O of/O his/O status/O left/O Jonathan/PERSON somewhat/O lonely/O ./O 
While/O at/O first/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON did/O n't/O have/O his/O future/O strength/O of/O will/O ,/O Dio/PERSON unwittingly/O became/O the/O catalyst/O of/O his/O growth/O by/O pushing/O him/O to/O the/O edge/O and/O humiliating/O his/O then/O -/O girlfriend/O Erina/PERSON Pendleton/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O he/O did/O have/O the/O kindness/O and/O courage/O to/O immediately/O jump/O to/O Erina/PERSON 's/O rescue/O against/O two/O bullies/O bigger/O than/O him/O despite/O not/O knowing/O her/O ./O 
First/O and/O foremost/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON strives/O to/O become/O his/O definition/O of/O a/O "/O true/O gentleman/O "/O as/O he/O carries/O his/O Joestar/O name/O with/O pride/O ,/O never/O betraying/O the/O code/O of/O honor/O he/O has/O set/O for/O himself/O and/O will/O treat/O any/O fellow/O human/O with/O respect/O unless/O they/O prove/O evil/O ./O 
Jonathan/PERSON also/O possesses/O a/O fierce/O inner/O strength/O and/O the/O drive/O to/O face/O and/O overcome/O conflict/O ,/O which/O Dio/O calls/O an/O "/O explosive/O power/O "/O ./O 
That/O drive/O ,/O fueled/O by/O his/O affection/O for/O his/O friends/O and/O loved/O ones/O ,/O enabled/O him/O to/O overcome/O the/O direst/O situations/O ,/O notably/O managing/O to/O save/O his/O wife/O Erina/PERSON when/O their/O boat/O was/O overcome/O with/O zombies/O and/O he/O was/O fatally/O hit/O in/O the/O throat/O ./O 
Jonathan/PERSON fights/O for/O what/O he/O believes/O in/O ,/O and/O once/O he/O is/O committed/O to/O something/O ,/O he/O wo/O n't/O back/O down/O until/O the/O deed/O is/O done/O ./O 
During/O his/O journey/O to/O find/O a/O cure/O for/O his/O father/O 's/O illness/O ,/O he/O was/O ambushed/O by/O a/O band/O of/O misfit/O hoodlums/O ./O 
He/O did/O not/O so/O much/O as/O flinch/O as/O he/O grasped/O an/O assailant/O 's/O knife/O within/O his/O hand/O ,/O saying/O he/O had/O much/O more/O riding/O on/O the/O fight/O than/O merely/O four/O fingers/O ./O 
As/O a/O gentleman/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON is/O also/O kind/O and/O positive/O ./O 
Jonathan/PERSON has/O a/O mindset/O where/O he/O tries/O to/O imagine/O the/O consequences/O his/O actions/O would/O have/O on/O other/O people/O ,/O even/O if/O they/O appear/O to/O be/O enemies/O ./O 
He/O is/O gentle/O and/O sympathetic/O ,/O feeling/O pain/O even/O as/O he/O vanquishes/O a/O zombified/O copper/O ./O 
Despite/O his/O skill/O in/O fighting/O ,/O he/O will/O never/O seriously/O harm/O a/O person/O without/O a/O valid/O reason/O ./O 
Even/O after/O everything/O Dio/PERSON has/O done/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON still/O considers/O him/O his/O brother/O ,/O and/O sheds/O tears/O for/O him/O ./O 
His/O courteous/O nature/O as/O well/O as/O his/O mental/O fortitude/O and/O ability/O to/O withstand/O fear/O and/O pain/O ,/O is/O the/O main/O reason/O Speedwagon/PERSON decides/O to/O aid/O him/O on/O his/O journey/O ./O 
During/O his/O life/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON has/O always/O had/O an/O impulse/O to/O save/O others/O ,/O beginning/O with/O Erina/PERSON ,/O and/O ending/O with/O his/O thought/O of/O a/O nearby/O baby/O just/O as/O he/O was/O agonizing/O over/O Dio/PERSON 's/O attack/O ./O 
Yet/O Jonathan/PERSON can/O feel/O righteous/O fury/O at/O the/O evilness/O of/O his/O foes/O and/O will/O conduct/O justice/O by/O vanquishing/O them/O ./O 
He/O admitted/O that/O his/O reason/O for/O fighting/O Dio/PERSON was/O n't/O out/O of/O duty/O for/O saving/O the/O world/O ,/O but/O to/O avenge/O his/O loved/O ones/O that/O Dio/O had/O killed/O ./O 
Moreover/O ,/O he/O has/O no/O pity/O for/O truly/O despicable/O individuals/O he/O is/O not/O familiar/O with/O such/O as/O Doobie/PERSON ./O 
With/O his/O courage/O and/O spirit/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON sets/O a/O legacy/O as/O the/O first/O JoJo/O of/O the/O series/O ./O 
Fascinated/O with/O the/O Stone/ORGANIZATION Mask/ORGANIZATION ,/O Jonathan/PERSON tried/O to/O study/O it/O and/O even/O took/O on/O the/O path/O of/O Archaeology/O ./O 
However/O ,/O not/O having/O thought/O of/O putting/O it/O on/O anyone/O ,/O Jonathan/PERSON did/O n't/O discover/O its/O true/O purpose/O himself/O Dio/O however/O was/O closely/O following/O in/O order/O to/O complete/O his/O plan/O ./O 
